<resources>
    <string name="app_name">GoslingLovelace</string>
    <string name="gosling">  James Gosling received a Bachelor of Science from the University of Calgary [4] and his M.A. and Ph.D. from Carnegie Mellon University.[2][5][6] He wrote a version of Emacs called Gosling Emacs (Gosmacs) while working toward his doctorate. He built a multi-processor version of Unix for a 16-way computer system[7] while at Carnegie Mellon University, before joining Sun Microsystems. He also developed several compilers and mail systems there.In March 2011, Gosling left Oracle to work at Google.[13] Six months later, he followed his colleague Bill Vass and joined a startup called Liquid Robotics.[1] In late 2016, Liquid Robotics was aquired by Boeing.[14] Following the aquisition, Gosling left Liquid Robotics to work at Amazon Web Services as Distinguished Engineer in May 2017.[15]
Gosling initially became known as the author of Gosling Emacs, and also invented the windowing system NeWS, which lost out to X Window because Sun did not give it an open source license. He is generally credited with having invented the Java programming language in 1994.[21][22][23] He created the original design of Java and implemented the language's original compiler and virtual machine.[24] Gosling traces the origins of the approach to his early graduate-student days, when he created a p-code virtual machine for the lab's DEC VAX computer, so that his professor could run programs written in UCSD Pascal. In the work leading to Java at Sun, he saw that architecture-neutral execution for widely distributed programs could be achieved by implementing a similar philosophy: always program for the same virtual machine.[25]
    </string>



    <string name="ada"> When she was a teenager, her mathematical talents led her to a long working relationship and friendship with fellow British mathematician Charles Babbage, also known as the father of computers, and in particular, Babbages work on the Analytical Engine. Lovelace first met him in June 1833, through their mutual friend, and her private tutor, Mary Somerville.
Between 1842 and 1843, Ada translated an article by Italian military engineer Luigi Menabrea on the engine, which she supplemented with an elaborate set of notes, simply called Notes. These notes contain what many consider to be the first computer program—that is, an algorithm designed to be carried out by a machine. Lovelaces notes are important in the early history of computers.On 16 January 1816 Adas mother, Annabella, at Byrons behest, left for her parents home at Kirkby Mallory, taking one-month-old Ada with her.[10] Although English law at the time gave fathers full custody of their children in cases of separation, Byron made no attempt to claim his parental rights[12] but did request that his sister keep him informed of Adas welfare.[13] On 21 April Byron signed the Deed of Separation, although very reluctantly, and left England for good a few days later.[14] Aside from an acrimonious separation, Annabella continually made allegations about Byrons immoral behaviour throughout her life.[15]
This set of events made Ada famous in Victorian society. Byron did not have a relationship with his daughter, and never saw her again. He died in 1824 when she was eight years old. Her mother was the only significant parental figure in her life.[16] Ada was not shown the family portrait of her father (covered in green shroud) until her twentieth birthday.[17] Her mother became Baroness Wentworth in her own right in 1856.
    </string>


</resources>